Guide to the Adele Fournet Papers MSS.516
Fales Library and Special Collections
Adele Fournet Papers
2008-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fournet, Adele
MSS.516
10.41 Gigabytes in 79 computer files and 4 archived websites.
1.91 Gigabytes in 52 audio files.
8.75 Gigabytes in 27 video files.
Adele Fournet is a composer, musician, video artist, and music producer based in Brooklyn, NY. The Adele Fournet Papers contain born digital materials created between 2008-2017 documenting Fournet's career and musical works. The collection includes audio and video files, an inventory spreadsheet and an archived copy of her website, adelefournet.com. The collection documents her solo work as well as her collaborations with other artists.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by title of project or publication, or format of material.
Custodial History
Websites are selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
Conditions Governing Access
Audio and video recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor. All other material in the collection is open to researchers.
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Take-down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information. If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials. If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to fales.library@nyu.edu. Please include the following in your notice: identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Scope and Contents
The Adele Fournet Papers contain born-digital materials created between 2008-2017 documenting Fournet's career and musical works. The collection includes audio and video files, an inventory spreadsheet, and an archived copy of her website, adelefournet.com. The collection documents her solo work as well as her collaborations with other artists in projects such as The Soon-Another and a string quartet. The website contains a short biography of the artist, a list of texts and scores, documentary videos, music and composition videos, and audio files of her works and performances. The website documents her work as a musician, producer, video artist, and composer, who has been involved as a percussionist, vocalist, and keyboard player in several ensembles in addition to composing.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Adele Fournet, October 2017. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2017.118 and 2017.185.
http://www.adelefournet.com was initially added as part of the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites Web Archive in 2017. In 2018, the crawling was discontinued and began being captured in the Avery Fisher Center: Adele Fournet Web Archive. Individual videos were added to better capture the videos embedded in http://www.adelefournet.com/. The accession numbers associated with the videos are 2019.045, 2019.058, 2021.022, and 2021.030. In December 2019, https://soundcloud.com/adelefournet/ and https://adelefournet.bandcamp.com/ was added to the web archives. The accession number associated with these websites is 2020.005.
Biographical Note
Adele Fournet is a musician, composer, music producer and video artist born in Fayetteville, AR and based in Brooklyn, NY. She works both as a solo artist and in collaborations with other artists.
Women composers; Singers; Percussion instrument music; Web sites.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.; Digital images.; Composers.
- Autodactyls -- Two Heads, 2011; cuid6165; 32.7 Megabytes in 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audio recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Berets of Mary Jean Place, 2017; cuid6179; 99.04 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_2)
  Video recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Book of Onion, 2015; cuid6166; 92.84 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_3)
- Celeste Krishna, 2016; cuid6167; 53.57 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_4)
- ColorWheel, 2015; cuid6164; 1.76 Gigabytes in 1 audio file and 1 video file.; 224.5 Megabytes in 1 audio file.; 1.54 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_5)
  Audio and video recordings are available for streaming with password authentication from NYU Libraries for researchers with prior approval based on the 2016 agreement with the donor.
- Electro Insides -- Don't Believe Them, 2017; cuid6168; 332.7 Megabytes in 6 audio files and 1 video file.; 197.8 Megabytes in 6 audio files.; 134.9 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_6)
- Electro Insides -- EP, 2015; cuid6169; 300.5 Megabytes in 5 audio files and 2 video files.; 142 Megabytes in 5 audio files.; 158.5 Megabytes in 2 video files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_7)
- For Dance, 2015; cuid6170; 27.98 Megabytes in 3 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_8)
- Humanimals, 2011-2012; cuid6181; 23.81 Megabytes in 2 video files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_9)
- La Puta Que Te Pano, 2012; cuid6171; 6.66 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_10)
- Ladies of Leisure, 2014; cuid6182; 747.8 Megabytes in 2 video files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_11)
- Metadata Spreadsheet, 2017; cuid6178; 10.45 kilobytes in 1 spreadsheet. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_12)
- On Death, 2013; cuid6183; 175.7 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_13)
- Por Fin Pano Paula, 2012; cuid6184; 94.89 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_14)
- Remembering Pauline Oliveros, 2016; cuid6185; 405 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_15)
- Schoreo, 2016; cuid6186; 1.01 Gigabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_16)
- Sin Killer, 2017; cuid6172; 51.46 Megabytes in 1 audio file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_17)
- Solo Piano, 2017; cuid6173; 974.4 Megabytes in 5 audio files and 3 video files.; 736.8 Megabytes in 3 video files.; 237.6 Megabytes in 5 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_18)
- String Quartet, 2008-2013; cuid6174; 172 Megabytes inn 4 audio files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_19)
- The Soon-Another -- Autodidact, 2013-2014; cuid6175; 2.69 Gigabytes in 10 audio files and 6 video files.; 357.2 Megabytes in 10 audio files.; 2.33 Gigabytes in 6 video files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_20)
- The Soon-Another -- Childish Spouses, 2015; cuid6176; 560.1 Megabytes in 5 audio files and 1 video file.; 193.7 Megabytes in 5 audio files.; 366.4 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_21)
- The Soon-Another -- Seggri, 2016-2017; cuid6177; 373.4 Megabytes in 3 audio files and 1 video file.; 125.1 Megabytes in 3 audio files.; 248.3 Megabytes in 1 video file. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_22)
- Caer Es Una Forma, 2016-2017; cuid6180; 207.2 Megabytes in 2 video files. (Box Electronic records, E-records FA_MSS_516_ER_23)
- Archived Websites, May 2017-ongoing; cuid6187; Fournet, Adele; 3 websites in 3 archived websites. (Box Electronic records)
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.adelefournet.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Soundcloud website was expanded to include cf-media.sndcdn.com and ec-media.soundcloud.com hosts.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
  Scope and Contents
  The website contains a short biography of the artist, a list of texts and scores, documentary, music and composition videos, and audio files, as well as her bandcamp and soundcloud pages. Fournet is a musician, producer, video artist, and composer, who has been involved as a percussionist, vocalist, and keyboard player in several ensembles. Capture of the site began in May 2017.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Fournet, Adele